如果你没有听过这个笑话  -
Stop me if you've heard this one.
两个工程师在编译他们的代码
Two engineers are compiling their code.
新手举手喊道：“哇 我的代码能编译！”
The newcomer raises his hands and shouts, "Woo, my code compiled!"
老手则会眯着眼睛喃喃道：
The veteran narrows her eyes and mutters,
“唔 我的代码居然能编译”
"Hm. My code compiled."
*BGM~*
如果你已经做过一段时间编程
If you've been in the coding game a little while,
当你开始思考失败这件事
something changes
看法可能就会有所不同
when you think about failure.
那些过去无法解决的问题
Things that used to look like impossible problems
如今开始看起来像一个更大的解决方案中的一个正常组成部分
begin to look like healthy parts of a larger solution.
那些你曾经称之为“失败”的东西
The stuff you used to call “failure",
现在看起来像是变相的成功
begins to look like success in disguise.
你开始希望你的代码无法通过编译
You expect your code to not compile.
你希望可以一路摆弄和实验它们
You expect to play and experiment all along the way,
调试和修订和重构这些代码
fiddling, revising, refactoring.
你正在收听的是红帽公司的原创播客节目《代码英雄》
I'm Saron Yitbarek, and this is Command Line Heroes,
我是主持人 Saron Yitbarek
an original podcast from Red Hat.
*BGM~*
老实说 那句“快速失败（fail fast）”的口号
That whole "fail fast" mantra, let's be honest,
经常被用来作为通往成功的捷径
it often gets used as a way to try and shortcut things towards success.
但是
But what if,
如果我们不是告诉彼此加快速度并快速失败
instead of telling each other to hurry up and fail fast,
而是鼓励彼此更好地失败呢？
we encourage each other to actually fail better.
《代码英雄》的第二季
Season Two of Command Line Heroes
将介绍的是开发工作中真实的体验：
is all about the lived experience of working in development,
“当我们生活在代码中
what it really feels like
到底感觉如何？
and how it really pans out
又是如何变化的？”
when we're living on the command line.
这也是为什么我们要用一整集的时间来讨论失败
And that's why we're devoting a whole episode to dealing with failure,
因为正是这些失败时刻促使我们适应它
because it's those moments that push us to adapt.
我们称之为“失败”的东西
The stuff we call failure,
是进化的心跳
it's the heartbeat of evolution,
而开源开发者正在拥抱这种进化
and open source developers are embracing that evolution.
当然 这说起来容易做起来难
Of course, that's a lot easier said than done.
*BGM~*
想象一下
Imagine this:
如果一首全新的莎士比亚的十四行诗被发现了
a brand-new sonnet from the man himself, Shakespeare, gets discovered.
网络上会兴起一阵热潮
There's a huge rush of interest online.
每个人都想去搜索它
Everybody's googling.
但这时
But then!
有个小小的设计缺陷导致了所谓的
This one little design flaw leads to something called,
“文件描述符耗尽”
"file descriptor exhaustion."
这会造成一连串的失败
That creates a cascading failure.
突然之间 能处理这些流量的服务器越来越少
Suddenly, you've got all that traffic moving across fewer and fewer servers.
很快 在 Google 上的“莎士比亚”搜索崩溃了
Pretty soon, Google's Shakespeare search has crashed,
并崩溃了一个多小时
and it stays crashed for over an hour.
现在 你丢掉了 12 亿次搜索查询
Now you've lost 1.2 billion search queries.
这是一场莎士比亚式的悲剧
It's a tragedy of Shakespearean proportions,
所有的一切
all playing out
在网站可靠性工程师（SRE）四处补救的同时上演
while site reliability engineers are scrambling to catch up.
“你也有份 布鲁图？”
*Et tu, Brute? *
*出自莎士比亚戏剧《恺撒》。是剧中凯撒角色的遗言。
这句拉丁文台词被用于表达凯撒发现刺杀者中包含其助手及养子，布鲁图斯（Brutus）后的震惊。
“那就倒下吧 凯撒！”
*Then fall, Caesar.*
*亦出自《凯撒》。是凯撒的最后一句台词。
不好意思 我打断一下
Okay, hate to break it to you.
但上面说的这个莎士比亚事件其实并不存在
The Shakespearean incident isn't real.
事实上
In fact,
这是一本书《SRE：Google 运维解密》中
it's part of a series of disastrous scenarios
一系列灾难性场景的一部分
in a book called, Site Reliability Engineering.
从这本书中学到的重要的一课就是
And one of the big lessons from that book is that
你必须超越灾难本身
you've got to look beyond the disaster itself.
这就是我的意思
Here's what I mean.
在这个莎士比亚的例子中
In the Shakespeare case,
当流量被集火到一个被牺牲的单独集群时
the query of death gets resolved
这个死亡查询问题就解决了
when that laser beam of traffic gets pushed onto a single, sacrificial cluster.
这为团队赢得了扩充容量的足够时间
That buys the team enough time to add more capacity.
但你不能就此止步
But you can't stop there.
尽管这个问题很糟糕
As bad as that issue was,
但解决它并不是真正的重点所在
resolving it isn't where the real focus should be.
因为失败不一定以痛苦告终
Because failure doesn't have to end in suffering,
失败也可以引导你的学习
failure can lead to learning.
嗨 我是 Jennifer Petoff
Hi, I'm Jennifer Petoff.
Jennifer 在谷歌工作
Jennifer works over at Google.
她是 SRE（站点可靠性工程）团队的高级项目经理
She's a senior program manager for their SRE team and leads Google's global SRE education program,
*站点可靠性工程 = SRE = site reliability engineering
也是 Google 全球 SRE 教学计划的领头人
She's a senior program manager for their SRE team and leads Google's global SRE education program,
*站点可靠性工程 = SRE = site reliability engineering
她也是这本描述了莎士比亚场景的书的作者之一
and she's also one of the authors of that book,
the one that described the Shakespeare scenario.
对于 Jennifer 来说
For Jennifer,
钻研这样的灾难才能使事情变得更好
digging into disasters like that is how things get better.
但前提是 你需要有敢于拥抱错误和意外的文化
But only if you have a culture where mistakes and surprises are embraced.
所以 让我们再拿莎士比亚举例子
So take the Shakespeare snafu again.
有一个直接的办法
There is a straightforward solution.
减少负载可以让你免于这种连锁故障
Load shedding can save you from that cascading failure.
但 真正的工作将在一切恢复正常之后开始
But the real work starts after things are back to normal.
重点在于事后分析报告
The real work is in the post-mortem.
事件解决后
After the incident is resolved,
我们会创建一个事后分析报告
a post-mortem would be created.
谷歌的每一个事件
Every incident at Google
都需要有一个事后分析和相应的行动项目
is required to have a post-mortem and corresponding action items
以防止将来再次出现问题
to prevent,
以及更有效地检测和缓解
but also to more effectively detect and mitigate similar incidents or whole classes of issues in the future.
未来出现类似事件或这类问题的可能
这是一个关键的区别
That's a key distinction right there.
不仅仅是解决这个特定事件
Not just solving for this particular incident,
而是看到这个事件告诉你的一系列问题
but seeing what the incident tells you about a class of issues.
真正有效的事后分析
Post-mortems, really effective ones,
不只是告诉你昨天哪里出现了问题
don't just tell you what went wrong yesterday.
而是让你对今天所做的工作
They give you insights about the work you're doing today,
以及对未来的计划有深刻的见解
and about what you're planning for the future.
这种更广泛的思想
That broader kind of thinking
灌输了对所有这些事故和失败的尊重
instills a respect for all those accidents and failures,
使它们成为日常工作生活中至关重要的一部分
makes them a vital part of everyday work life.
所以
So,
一个真正好的事后分析
a really good post–mortem addresses
不仅仅要解决手头的单个问题
more than just the single issue at hand,
它针对的是整一类问题
it addresses the whole class of issues.
事后分析的重点是什么地方做对了
And the post-mortems focus on what went well,
什么地方做错了
what went wrong,
在何处幸运的解决了问题
where we got lucky,
以及可以采取哪些优先行动
and what prioritized action we can take
来确保这种情况不会再次发生
to make sure this doesn't happen again.
如果你不采取行动
If you don't take action,
历史必将重演
history is destined to repeat itself.
在谷歌
At Google,
人们关注的是不追责的事后分析（blameless post-mortems）
There's a focus on Blameless Post-mortems.
这就造成了根本的不同
and that makes all the difference.
如果出了问题而没有人要责怪
If nobody's to blame when something goes wrong,
那么每个人都可以诚实地挖掘错误
then everybody can dig into errors in an honest way
真正地从错误中吸取教训
and really learn from them
而不必掩盖任何线索 也不必争吵
without covering tracks, or arguing.
这些不追责的事后分析
Those blameless post-mortems
已经成为谷歌文化的一个重要组成部分
have become a key part of the culture at Google,
其结果是 工作环境中的人们不必害怕失败
and the result is a workplace where failure isn't something to be afraid of.
失败成了常态的一部分
It's normalized.
谷歌如何看待失败？
How does Google look at failure?
100% 的在线时间是一个不可能的目标
100% of time is an impossible goal,
如果你认为这是可以实现的
like, you're kidding yourself
那就是在自欺欺人
if you think that's achievable.
所以
So
失败总会发生 只是时间和方式的问题
failure's going to happen, it's just a matter of when and how.
在谷歌 失败是值得庆祝的
Failure is celebrated at Google,
因为我们可以从中吸取教训
so it's something we can learn from,
而事后分析也会在团队中广泛分享
and post-mortems are shared widely among teams
以确保学到的东西可以广泛使用
to make sure that the things that are learned are widely available.
错误是不可避免的
Failure is inevitable,
但你永远不想以同样的方式失败两次
but you never want to fail the same way twice.
犯错是人之常情
To err is human, but to err repeatedly
但反复犯错是可以避免的
is something that would be better avoided.
*BGM*
听到 Jennifer 讨论失败的方式
It's so interesting
这真是太有趣了
hearing the way Jennifer talks about failures,
因为她就像是在试着看透那些错误一样
because it's like she's leaning into those mistakes.
比如 当事情出错的时候
Like, when things go wrong,
这意味着你已经走到了一个可以挖掘价值的地方
it means you've arrived at a place you can actually mine for value.
你会现场处理这种情况
You deal with the situation in real time,
但在事后 你应该花时间把发生的事情写出来
but then afterwards taking time to write up what happened
让别人可以从中学习
so that others can learn from that.
发生事件时
With any incidents,
你会付出代价
you pay the price when it happens,
如果你不写出事后分析
and you're not re–collecting some of that cost
并真正从这个经验中吸取教训
if you don't write up a post–mortem
你就不会重新收回解决问题所花费的成本
and actually learn from that experience,
在我看来 这是至关重要的一课
and I think that's a critical lesson.
在谷歌 我们坚信不追责文化
We believe very strongly here at Google in a blameless culture.
你不会因为指责别人而获得任何好处
You don't gain anything by pointing fingers at people,
那只会让人们去掩盖失败
and that just incents people to cover up failure,
而失败 总是会发生
which is going to happen, regardless.
这里非常重要的一点是
It's so important here
要记住 Jennifer 之前说过的一些话
to remember something Jennifer said earlier,
在工作中不出错是一种幻想
that error-free work is a fantasy.
总会有出错的地方
There will always be things that go wrong.
归根结底这是思想的转变
What it comes down to is a shift in thinking.
我们可以抛弃那种
We can put away that idea
认为只有一个单一的、可确定的最终目标
that there's a single, definable end goal,
即一切最终都会按照我们想象的方式发展的想法
where everything will finally go the way we imagined.
我们希望达到的不存在错误的状态并不存在
There is no single there that we're trying to get to,
事实证明
and it turns out,
这种心态转变能起到极大的积极作用
that's a hugely powerful and positive thing.
*BGM*
谷歌拥抱失败的做法很有意义
Google's push for embracing failure makes a lot of sense.
超级实用
Super practical.
但我想知道
But I wanted to know,
这只是口头上的么？
is this just lip-service?
我们是否有一些具体的让事情变得更好的失败例子
Do we have some concrete examples of failure actually making things better,
或者这只是一种当我们进行第 200 次编译时
or is it all just a way to make ourselves feel better
让我们感觉更好的一种方法
when we're hitting compile for the 200th time?
事实证明
Turns out,
有人可以回答这个问题
there's someone who can answer that.
我的名字叫 Jessica Rudder
My name is Jessica Rudder.
我是 Github 的软件工程师
I'm a software engineer at GitHub.
Jessica 在 Github 经历过失败
Jessica has seen her share of failure over at GitHub.
从某种意义上说
It's a failure arena,
这是一个失败的舞台
in one sense,
在这一过程中
and along the way,
她收集了一些“失败是成功之母”的真实案例
she's collected some stories about times when failure was the doorway to massive success.
比如这个：
Like this one:
*BGM*
90 年代有个游戏开发公司
So there was a game development company
正在开发一款全新的游戏
that was working on a brand-new game in the '90s.
从本质上说 这是一款赛车游戏
Essentially, it was a racing game,
但他们的转折之处在于
but their twist on it was that
将其改为街头赛车
it was going to be street racing.
所以当赛车手在街道上飙车时
So as the racers are racing through the streets,
他们不仅是在互相飙车
they're not only racing each other,
而且他们也是与在追赶他们的警车（非玩家角色）赛车
but they're also NPCs (non-player characters) that are cop cars that are chasing them down.
如果一辆警车抓住了你
And if a cop car catches you,
它会让你靠边停车
it's supposed to pull you over
然后你就输掉了比赛
and then you lose the race.
然后他们把这些代码衔接起来
So they get this code all wired up,
然后开始运行
and they start running it,
他们发现
and what they discovered is that
他们完全调校错了算法：
they completely calibrated the algorithm wrong,
警车只是尖叫着从侧街冲出来
and instead of the cop cars chasing the players' vehicles,
直接撞向玩家的车
they would just come screaming out of side streets
而不是追赶玩家的车
and slam right into them.
*翻车声*
所以这里简直是一团糟
So it was just a total mess.
他们想 不要惊慌
And instead of freaking out,
让我们继续前进 看看人们如何看待它的
they thought, let's go ahead and see how people like it,
这样我们就知道该怎么调整算法了
and that way we know what to tweak about the algorithm.
所以他们把它交给了游戏测试人员
So they sent it over to the play testers,
他们发现游戏测试人员
and what they found was that the play testers
在逃离警察
had way more fun
并试图躲避被这些流氓暴力警车抓捕的过程中
running away from the cops and trying to dodge being captured by these rogue, violent cop cars
获得了比赛车更多的乐趣
than they ever had with just the racing game itself.
而事实上 它是如此的有趣
And it was so much fun, in fact,
以至于开发团队改变了他们为游戏打造的整个理念
that the development team shifted the entire concept that they were building the game around.
你能猜出这是怎么回事吗？
Can you guess where this is goin
所以我们才有了《侠盗猎车手》
And that's how we ended up with Grand Theft Auto.
即 GTA = Grand Theft Auto
我的意思是 它确实是有史以来最畅销的电子游戏
I mean, it's literally the best-selling video game franchise of all time,
它能存在的全部原因都是
and the whole reason it exists is
因为当时他们没有使用正确的算法时所导致的失误
because when they failed to get the algorithm right,
他们想 好吧
they thought, well,
让我们来试试
let's try it out.
看看我们得到了什么
Let's see what we've got,
看看我们能从中学到什么
and let's see what we can learn from it.
*Epic Music*
很神奇吧？
Sort of amazing, right?
但这里有个技巧
But here's the trick.
《侠盗猎车手》团队在遭遇失败时必须保持宽容
The Grand Theft Auto team had to stay receptive when they were hit with a failure.
他们必须保持好奇心
They had to stay curious.
所以 如果这些开发者没有开放的思想
So if those developers hadn't been open–minded about it,
并决定从这个错误中去学到什么
and decided to see what they could learn from this mistake,
我们将永远不会有《侠盗猎车手》
we would never have had Grand Theft Auto.
我们只能玩一些无聊的、普通的街头赛车游戏了
We would have had some boring, run–of–the–mill street race game.
让我们再就游戏主题讨论一分钟
Sticking with the game theme for a minute,
类似的事情也发生在《寂静岭》的制作过程中
something similar happened when Silent Hill was being produced.
这是一款3A级大作
This was a huge, triple-A game - big-time production.
但他们遇到了严重的弹出问题
But they had serious problems with pop-up.
局部景观的处理速度不够快
Parts of the landscape weren't being processed fast enough,
因此突然之间
so all of a sudden
*口哨声*
你会突然发现一堵墙或一条小路突然冒出来
you get a wall or a bit of road popping up out of nowhere.
这是一个破坏性的问题
This was a deal-breaker problem,
而且他们的开发已经到非常后期
and they were late in their development cycle.
他们是怎么做的？
So what do they do?
完全放弃游戏
Scrap the game entirely?
举手投降？
Throw their hands up?
还是将错就错？
Or embrace the problem itself?
他们所做的就是让这个世界充满了非常浓郁、诡异的雾气
What they did was fill the world with a very dense, eerie fog.
因为事实证明
Because fog, as it turns out,
雾对处理器来说非常容易渲染
is really easy for the processors to render
而且不会有任何延迟
and not get any kind of delays.
而且另外
But additionally,
雾使你看不到远处的东西
fog prevents you from seeing things at a distance,
所以在现实中 那些建筑物仍然会突然出现
so in reality, those buildings are still popping in,
但由于雾遮挡了你的视线 你看不到它们
but you can't see it anymore because the fog is blocking your view.
所以当它们进入视野时
So when they do come into view,
它们已经被渲染了
they're already rendered,
看起来它们是从雾中出来的
and it looks like they're coming out of the fog, instead.
雾是变得如此受欢迎
The fog became so well-loved
它基本上被认为是《寂静岭》系列中的一个特点
that it's basically considered another character in the Silent Hill franchise.
它限制了玩家的视野
It makes the game play way scarier
使游戏变得更加恐怖
by limiting the player's vision.
甚至当处理器的速度快到不需要再掩盖那些弹出的时候
And even when the processors got so fast that they didn't need to cover up those pop-ups anymore,
他们也保留了雾气
they kept the fog.
你无法在没有雾的情况下玩《寂静岭》
You cannot have a Silent Hill game without fog.
而这些雾最初所做的一切都是在掩盖一个错误
And all that fog was doing initially was covering up a mistake.
我喜欢这个故事！
I love it!
他们拥抱失败而不是逃避失败
They saved a major development by embracing their failure
从而挽救了一个重大的发展
instead of running from it.
这条关于不怕失败的原则也适用于个人的小事
And that rule about not fearing failure applies to little, individual things, too,
而不仅仅是全公司的决策
not just company-wide decisions.
从容面对失败是我们一点一点地变得更好的方法
Looking failure calmly in the face is how we get better, bit by bit.
很多时候人们脑子里想的太多了
A lot of times people get too much into their own head
他们认为失败意味着我不擅长某样东西
and they think a failure means I'm bad at x.
并不是代码坏了我还不知道如何修复它
It's not, oh, this code is broken and I don't know how to fix it,
而是“我不知道如何编写 JavaScript”
yet. It's, “I don't know how to write JavaScript.”
而且 你永远不会通过说
And you are never going to learn what you need to learn by saying,
“我不知道如何编写 JavaScript”来学习所需的知识
“I don't know how to write JavaScript.”
但是如果你能确定
But if you can identify,
“哦 我不知道如何在 JavaScript 中实现这个循环”
oh, I don't know how to make this loop work in JavaScript,
那么你可以通过 Google 找到答案
then you have something that you can Google,
而且效果很好
and it just works perfect.
我是说 你仍然需要努力
I mean, you're still going to struggle,
但你遇到的麻烦会少的多
but you're going to struggle a whole lot less.
*BGM*
因此 无论你是新开发人员还是大型工作室的负责人
So our mistakes nudge us toward bigger things, those experiments,
我们的错误将我们推向更大的领域
those fails, those heroic attempts,
那些实验、失败、英勇的尝试
they make up most of the journey,
它们占据了旅程的大部分
whether you're a new developer or the head of a major studio.
在我所熟悉和喜爱的开源社区里
And nowhere is that more true than
这是最真实的情况了
in the open source communities I've come to know and love.
失败在开源中可能是一件美好的事情
Failure can be a beautiful thing in open source,
这就是我们接下来的故事
and that's where our story goes next.
*BGM*
我们在前面看到了失败是如何带来惊喜
We saw earlier how failing well can lead to happy surprises,
- 那些我们甚至不知道自己想尝试的事情
things we didn't even know we wanted to try.
在最好的情况下
And at its best,
开源开发文化正好符合这一点
open source development culture hits that mark.
它让失败变得正常
It makes failure okay.
为了理解这种愿意失败的想法是如何被引入开源开发的
To understand how that willingness to fail gets baked into open source development,
我和 Jen Krieger 聊了聊
I got chatting with Jen Krieger.
她是 Red Hat 的首席敏捷架构师
She's Red Hat's chief agile architect.
我们讨论了对开源失败的态度
We talked about attitudes toward failure in open source,
以及这些态度是如何塑造无限可能的
and how those attitudes shape what's possible.
请听：
Take a listen:
我想谈谈这个口号
I want to touch on this mantra,
我觉得这也许是一个很好的表达方式
I feel is probably a good way to put it.
“快速失败 打破现状”
The "fail fast and break things,"
这几乎是为我们社区所设计的一个巨大的召集口号
which is a big rally cry, almost, I feel like, for our community.
你怎么看？
What are your thoughts on that?
我对此有很多想法
I have a lot of thoughts on that.
我也觉得你会有
I thought you might.
快速失败 在失败中前进
Fail fast, fail forward, fail quickly
所有这些都是一个意思
—all those things.
所以 在我刚刚参加工作的时候
So to put that into context, in the early days of my career,
我在一家没有失败空间的公司工作
I worked in a company where there was no room for failure.
如果你做错了什么事情
If you did something wrong,
你就可以准备辞职了
you brought down the one application.
任何人都不能做错事
There was really no way,
没有任何空间、途径允许你犯错
no room, really, for anybody to do anything wrong.
这令人们困扰
And that just really wraps people around the axle,
你绝对没有失败的余地
that idea that you have absolutely no room for failure,
导致我们几乎陷入一场文化运动
led us into almost like a cultural movement,
《代码英雄》第一季有关于敏捷开发和 DevOps 的内容！
愿意的话 这会催生出一个很棒词  - 敏捷
if you would, that then spawned into that wonderful word, agile,
《代码英雄》第一季有关于敏捷开发和 DevOps 的内容！
以及催生出另一个很棒的词  - DevOps
into the wonderful word, DevOps.
《代码英雄》第一季有关于敏捷开发和 DevOps 的内容！
当我看到这些词的时候
When I look at those words,
我看到的是
all I'm seeing is that
我们只是要求团队做一系列非常小的实验
we're simply asking teams to do a series of very small experiments
帮助他们修正方向
that help them course-correct.
这是个
It's about,
哦 你已经做出了选择
oh, you've made a choice,
而这实际上是一件积极的事情
and that's actually a positive thing.
你可能会做一个冒险的决定
You might take a risky decision,
然后你赢了 因为你做出了正确的决定
and then you win, because you've made the right decision.
或者反之 就是你做了错误的决定
Or the other side, which is, you've made the wrong decision
然后你明白了 那不是正确的方向
and you understand now that that wasn't the right direction to go in.
是的 这是有道理的
Yeah, that makes sense.
所以 当你
So when you think about
把“快速失败 打破现状”当成这个运动的时候
"fail fast and break things" as being this movement,
感觉在如何失败
it feels like there's still some structure,
如何以正确的方式失败上还是有一些方式
some best practices in how to fail,
有一些最佳的实践的
how to do that the right way.
那么 如何以一种正确的方式失败
What are some of the best practices
有哪些最佳实践和原则呢？
and the principles around failing in a way that is good in the end?
我总是喜欢告诉工程师
I always like to tell engineers
他们需要尽可能地让软件出错 尽快地让它出错
that they need to break the build as early and as often as possible.
一旦错误发生 且他们已经意识到其发生
If they're breaking their build and they're aware that they have broken the build
他们在当下就有机会真正修复它
they have the opportunity in the moment to actually fix it.
而这一切都围绕着“反馈循环（feedback loops）”这个概念
And it's all wrapped around that concept of feedback loops,
确保你在工作中得到的反馈循环尽可能短
and ensuring that the feedback loops that you're getting on the work that you're doing are as small as possible.
所以在开源开发中
And so in open source development,
我提交了一个补丁
I submit a patch,
然后有人说 “出于这九个原因 我不会接受你的补丁”
and somebody says, “I'm not going to accept your patch for these nine reasons,”
或者“我认为你的补丁很棒 继续吧”
or “I think your patch is great, move forward.”
或者 你提交了一个补丁
Or, you might be submitting a patch
但是机器人告诉你它失败了
and having a bot tell you that it's failed
因为它没有正确构建
because it hasn't built properly.
有各种不同类型的反馈
There's all sorts of different types of feedback.
然后在开源开发中
And then in open source development,
你可能会遇到更长的反馈循环
you might also have longer feedback loops
你可能会说 “我想设计这个新功能
where you say, “I want to design this new functionality,
但我不确定应该制订些什么规则
but I'm not entirely sure what all the rules should be.
有人能帮我设计吗？”
Can somebody help me design that?”
因此 你进入了一个漫长的过程
And so you go into this long process
在这个过程中 你要进行长时间的对话 对细节进行讨论
where you're having long and detailed conversations
而人们参与进来 提出最好的创意
where folks are participating and coming up with the best idea.
所以有各种各样的反馈循环可以帮助你完成这一过程
And so there's all sorts of different feedback loops that can help you accomplish that.
Jennifer 认为 每个公司的反馈循环看起来都不一样
Jen figures those feedback loops can look different for every company.
它们是可定制的
They're customizable,
能以上百种不同方式运行
and people can make them work in 100 different ways.
但重点是 她甚至没有把它们称为失败或错误
But the point is, she's not even calling them failures or mistakes.
她只是称它们为“反馈循环”
She's just calling them, "feedback loops."
这是一个有机系统
It's an organic system.
这是一种思考整个过程的健康方式
Such a healthy way of thinking about the whole process.
与此同时
Meanwhile,
对这些小毛病的另外一种态度却产生了完全相反的效果
there's one attitude toward those little glitches that has the exact opposite effect.
有些组织所做的事情是完全错误的
There are things that organizations do that are just flat-out the wrong thing to do.
嗯是啊
Mm-hmm (affirmative).
让你的领导团队（或者 总体而言 你所在的组织）
Having your leadership team, or, at a very high level, the organization thinking that
羞辱做错事情的人
shaming people for doing something wrong
或者在绩效结果方面灌输恐惧
or instilling fear in relation to performance results;
就像是
and that looks like,
“如果你工作做得不好 就拿不到奖金”
“If you don't do a good job, you won't get a bonus,”
或者“如果你工作做得不好 我会把你列入绩效计划 “
or “If you don't do a good job, I'm going to put you on a performance plan.”
这些都是会产生敌意的事情
Those are the types of things that create hostility.
她描述的场景 即是未能成功面对失败
What she's describing there is a failure fail.
不能接受失败就是失败
A failure to embrace what failure can be.
她也在呼应 Jennifer Petoff 的态度 对吧？
And she's echoing Jennifer Petoff's attitude too, right?
就是我们在这集开头提到的 不追责的事后分析？
That idea about blame-free post-mortems we heard about at the top of the episode?
是的 这很有趣
Yeah, that's interesting.
就好像 如果我们在团队协作的方式上要求更严格一点
It's like if we are a little bit more strict around how we work together,
或者只是更用心 更有目的性地一起工作
or maybe just more mindful, more purposeful in how we work together,
我们几乎就会被迫在失败中表现得更好
we will be almost forced to be better at our own failure.
是的
Yes.
有一些公司已经学会了这一点
And there's companies out there that have learned this already,
而且他们很久以前就学会了
and they've learned it a long time ago,
丰田就是一个很好的例子
and Toyota is a perfect example of a company that
他们接受了这种不断学习和改进的理念
embraces this concept of continuous learning and improvement in a way that
这是我在其他公司很少看到的
I rarely see at companies.
就是这样一种想法
There is just this idea that
每个人都能随时指出什么出了错
anyone at any point can point out something that isn't working properly.
不管他们是谁 在公司的哪个级别
It doesn't matter who they are, what level of the company they're in.
在他们的文化中 认为这是对的
It's just understood in their culture that that's okay.
这种持续学习和改进的环境
And that environment of continuous learning and improvement,
我想说 是一种领先的实践
I would say, would be one of those leading practices,
这是我希望公司能够做到的事情
the things that I would expect a company to do
能够适应失败并允许它发生
to be able to accommodate failure and to allow it to occur.
嗯 没错
Mm-hmm (affirmative). Yeah.
如果你问的是为什么事情进展不顺利
If you're asking questions about why things aren't going well,
而不是试图隐藏错误 或责怪别人
instead of pointing fingers or trying to hide things,
这就会造成完全不同的情况
it creates an entirely different situation.
它会改变对话的走向
Changes the conversation.
这很有趣 因为你之前提到过
And it's interesting because you mentioned earlier how the break things
“快速失败 打破现状”这句话是这种文化
"fail fast and break things" mantra was this culture,
这种对过去做事方式的反击
this kind of push-back against the way things used to be done.
但这听起来似乎是一种口头禅
But it sounds like that mantra
也许创造了另一种在公司内部、技术团队内部的协作方式
has also created maybe a different way that teams work within a company, within a tech team.
再给我讲讲这个问题
Tell me a little bit more about that.
它是如何改变了开发人员看待自己角色的方式
How has it changed the way developers see their roles
以及他们与公司其他人互动的方式?
and how they interact with other people in the company.
我早期和工程师一起工作的时候差不多是这样的
My early days of working with engineers pretty much looked like,
工程师们都坐在一个小区域
the engineers all sat in a small area.
他们互相交谈
They all talked to one another.
他们从未真正与任何商业人士进行过交流
They never really interacted with any of the business people.
他们从来没有真正理解他们的任何需求
They never really understood any of their incoming requirements,
我们花了很多时间 只是专注于如何不失败
and we spent an awful lot of time really focused on what they needed to be successful,
而那不一定是企业实际完成工作所需的东西
and not necessarily what the business needed to actually get their work done.
所以 它更像是
So it was much more of a,
*Saron Yitbarek的赞同*
“我是一个工程师 我要怎样实现这个功能？”
“I'm an engineer, what do I need in order to code this piece of functionality?”
我观察到 如今 在几乎每一个我与之合作过的团队中
What I observe today in pretty much every team that I work with,
对话方式已经发生了巨大的变化
the conversation has shifted significantly to not,
“作为工程师我需要什么才能完成工作”
“What do I need as an engineer to get my job done,”
变成了“客户或者用户需要怎样
but “What does the customer, or what does the user need
才会觉得我做的功能
to actually feel like this piece of functionality that I'm making
对他们来说是成功的？
is going to be successful for them?
他们如何使用产品？
How are they using the product?
我该怎样做才能让他们更轻松？”
What can I do to make it easier for them?”
很多这样的对话已经改变了
A lot of those conversations have changed,
我认为这就是为什么如今的公司
and I think that's why companies are doing better today
更善于提供有意义的技术
on delivering technology that makes sense.
我还想说的是 我们发布得越快
I will also say that the faster we get at releasing,
就越容易知道我们的假设是否正确、
the easier it is for us to know whether or not our assumptions and our decisions are actually coming true.
我们的决定是否明智
所以 如果我们对用户需求做了假设
So, if we make an assumption about what a user might want,
在此之前 我们需要等待
before, we were having to wait,
诸如一年到两年的时间 才能确定这是不是真的
like, a year to two years to really find out whether or not that was actually true.
*Saron Yitbarek的赞同*
而现在
Now,
如果你看看亚马逊或奈飞的模式
if you look at the model of an Amazon or Netflix,
你会发现 他们每天会对客户需求作出数百次假设
they're releasing their assumptions about what their customers want, like, hundreds of times a day.
他们从使用他们的应用程序的人们那里得到的反馈
And the response they get from folks using their applications
会告诉他们他们是否在做用户需要他们做的事情
will tell them whether or not they're doing what it is the users need them to be doing.
是的 这听起来需要更多的合作
Yeah, and it sounds like it requires more cooperation,
因为即使是你之前提出的关于
because even the piece of advice you gave earlier about
构建软件、让它出错、多让它出错的建议
build, break the build, break it often.
这就需要工程团队（或开发人员）与 DevOps 保持步调一致
That kind of requires the engineering team or the developers to be more in step with DevOps, right,
以便使之出错
in order for them to break it,
并了解尽早发布、经常发布会带来何种影响
and to see what that looks like to do those releases early and to do them often.
听起来这需要双方更多的合作
It sounds like it requires more cooperation between the two.
是的 对于拥有“敏捷教练”这个头衔的人
Yeah, and it's always amusing to somebody who has that title,
或者以我作为首席敏捷架构师看来 总是很有趣
agile coach, or in my case, chief agile architect,
因为《敏捷宣言》的初衷是让人们从不同的角度来考虑这些事情
because the original intent of the Agile Manifesto is to get folks to think about those things differently.
我们通过开发和帮助别人开发
We are uncovering better ways of developing software
来发现更好的开发软件的方法
by doing it and helping others do it.
它确实是敏捷开发的初衷 它的核心、根本和基础
It is really the core, heart, and foundation of what agile is supposed to do.
因此 如果你快进 10 年或者 15 年
And so, if you fast forward the 10, 15+ years
直到 DevOps 的到来
to the arrival of DevOps
并坚持持续集成、持续部署
and the insistence that we have continuous integration and deployment.
我们有监控
We have monitoring,
*《代码英雄》系列以“墙”来指代开发者和维护者之间的隔阂。
我们开始以不同的方式思考如何将代码扔出墙外
we start thinking differently about throwing code over the wall.
*《代码英雄》系列以“墙”来指代开发者和维护者之间的隔阂。
所有这些东西都是我们最初开始讨论敏捷时应该想到的
All that stuff is really what we were supposed to be thinking back when we originally started talking about agile.
嗯 绝对是的
Mm-hmm (affirmative).
所以 不管人们如何实践这种面对失败的方式
Absolutely. So regardless of how people implement this idea of failure,
我认为 我们都会同意一点：
I think that we can both agree that
接受失败、 将失败规范化只是过程的一部分
the acceptance of failure, the normalizing of failure is just a part of the process,
是一件应做的事
something that we need to do,
一件可行的事
something that happens that we can manage,
一件可以用“正确的方式”做的事
that we can maybe do the "right way,"
这是一件好事 它对开源有好处
is a good thing. It has done some good for open source.
说说它的好处吧
Tell me about some of the benefits of having this new movement,
“接受失败是必须的一步”的新文化的优点
this new culture of accepting failure as part of the process.
看着这个过程发生是一件美妙的事情
It's a beautiful thing to watch that process happen.
对一个人来说 从一个他们害怕发生错误、害怕担责的环境
For somebody to go from being really in a situation where they're fearful of what might happen,
到一个他们可以尝试实验、尝试成长、尝试找出正确答案的环境
to a place in which they can try to experiment and try to grow, and try to figure out what might be the right answer.
真的很高兴 就像它们已经盛开花朵
It's really great to see. It's like they blossom.
他们的士气提高了
Their morale improves,
他们真正意识到他们可以拥有的是什么
they actually realize that they can own what it is that they are.
他们可以自己做决定
They can make decisions for themselves,
而不必等待别人为他们做决定
they don't have to wait for somebody to make the decision for them.
失败即自由
Failure as freedom.
啊 我喜欢!
Ah, I love it!
Jen Krieger 是红帽公司的首席敏捷架构师
Jen Krieger is Red Hat's chief agile architect.
*BGM*
并不是所有的开源项目
Not all open source projects reach the fame and success of big ones,
都像 Rails、Django 或 Kubernetes 那样声名鹊起
like Rails or Django, or Kubernetes.
事实上 大多数都没有
In fact, most don't.
大多数都是只有一个贡献者的小项目
Most are smaller projects with just a single contributor.
解决一小群开发人员面临的小问题的小众项目
Niche projects that solve little problems that a small group of developers face,
或者它们已经被抛弃
or they've been abandoned
很久没有人碰了
and haven't been touched in ages.
但它们仍然有价值
But they still have value.
事实上 很多这样的项目仍然非常有用
In fact, a lot of those projects are still hugely useful,
Saron 你的用词有点吓到我了（划掉）
可以被回收、升级 被其他项目蚕食
getting recycled, upcycled, cannibalized by other projects.
Saron 你的用词有点吓到我了（划掉）
而另一些人通过他们的错误启发我们
And others simply inspire us,
教导我们
teach us by their very instructive wrongness.
因为在一个健康的、开放的舞台上
Because failure, in a healthy, open source arena,
失败会带给你比胜利更好的东西
gives you something better than a win.
它给了你洞察力
It gives you insight.
尽管有那些死胡同
And here's something else.
尽管有各种冒险的尝试和惊呼
Despite all those dead ends,
但开源项目的数量每年都在翻倍
the number of open source projects is doubling about every year, despite all the risky attempts and Hail Marys;
我们的社区正在繁荣
our community is thriving,
事实证明
and it turns out,
并非是“尽管存在失败 我们依然繁荣”
we're not thriving despite our failures,
我们正是因失败而繁荣
we're thriving because of them.
下一集预告
Next episode,
DevOps 世界中 安全性如何变化
how security changes in a DevOps world.
持续部署意味着安全正在渗透到开发的每个阶段
Constant deployment means security's working its way into every stage of development,
这正在改变我们的工作方式
and that is changing the way we work.
同时 如果你想了解更多关于开源文化的知识
Meantime, if you want to learn more about open source culture
以及我们如何改变围绕失败的文化
and how we can all change the culture around failing,
请访问 redhat.com/commandlineheroes  免费资源等着你
check out the free resources waiting for you at redhat.com/commandlineheroes.
《代码英雄》是红帽的原创播客
Command Line Heroes is an original podcast from Red Hat.
你可以在 Apple Podcast、Google Podcast
Listen for free on Apple Podcast, Google Podcast,
或是其他你喜欢的途径免费收听
or wherever you do your thing.
我是 Saron Yitbarek
I'm Saron Yitbarek.
坚持编程 下期再见
Until next time, keep on coding.